

7322725914 chris.tierney3@gmail.com 7575 E 29th PI #3131, Denver, CO 80238

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a dynamic worker with years of competitive experience I gained through snowboarding at the professional level. The dedication I put into the sport has carried over with me to every job or hobby I've done since. Developing requires equally engaging concentration. I'm confident that with my skills as a developer and competitor I would make a great addition to your company.

SKILLS

- Discipline
- Competitive, trustworthy and determined worker
- HTML & CSS

- Time management
- Proficient in the usage of APIs
- Javascript

EXPERIENCE

Student, University of Denver, Dec 2021 - Current, Denver, Colorado

- Through the University of Denver's full stack web development bootcamp I learned the necessary skills to succeed as a developer.
- Consumed and retained knowledge in a rigorously fast paced environment.

Volunteer, Make-A-Wish, Oct 2021 - Current, Denver, CO

- Assisted with planning, coordinating and purchasing items for Wishes.
- Built relationships with patients and their family member to develop trust and carry out Wishes with respect, understanding, and support.

Day Trader, Self Employed, May 2020 - Current, Denver, CO

- Analyzed data across multiple platforms to minimize risk with each transaction.
- Created strict rules for each trade to avoid unnecessary losses while maximizing profits resulting in the portfolio growing by roughly 500%.
- Gained skills in chart reading using tools like VWAP, RSI, and EMA.

Server, Holy Sushi Inc, Dec 2018 - Jul 2020, Boulder, CO

- Handled multiple tables at once with high service quality.
- Offered suggestions to customers to increase daily sales and surpass upsell expectations.
- Gained familiarity with menu ingredients and cooking processes to cater to customers with specific inquiries.

Intern, Seaport Global Inc, May 2017 - Aug 2017, New York, NY

• Rigorously analyzed data in the Industrials, Consumer, Financials, Materials,

Transportation, Energy, and Power sectors of equity research.

- Filed and retrieved documents and entered company data and metrics into databases.
- Created detailed presentations for supervisors, head analysts, investors, and clients.
- Became proficient in the use of the Bloomberg Terminal.

Professional Snowboarder, Mervin Manufacturers, Oakley, Neff Headwear, Nov 2013 - Apr 2017, Breckenridge, CO

- Traveled, trained, and competed at the professional level garnering multiple podium and top 10 finishes in some of the most recognizable events in snowboarding.
- Arranged travel plans for up to month stays both domestically and internationally.
- Gained leadership experience through helping teammates with learned skills, morale, and knowledge through competitive experience.
- Developed strong sense of discipline, work ethic and time management.

EDUCATION

Certificate of Completion, Web Development **University of Denver** - Denver, CO

Jun 2022

High School Diploma

May 2012

Stratton Mountain School - Stratton Mountain, VT

• Student Athlete

LINKS

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-tierney-833611180/
- https://github.com/christierney3
- https://christierney3.github.io/My-Porfolio/